Franz Boas Papers 1862-1942 Mss.B.B61.inventory7 Mss.B.B61.inventory07
American Philosophical Society
- Franz Boas Papers - Correspondents J
  - Jochelson, Waldemar (Box 48)
    - To Boas, 1907 Feb. 20
    - To Boas, 1907 Feb. 25; 3p.
    - To Boas, 1907 Mar. 5; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1907 Mar. 12; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1907 Mar. 18
    - To Boas, 1907 Mar. 21; 4p.
    - To Boas, 1907 Mar. 25
    - To Boas, 1907 Apr. 3
    - To Boas, 1907 Apr. 5; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1907 Apr. 18
    - To Boas, 1907 May 2; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1907 May 11
    - To Boas, 1907 May 15
    - To Boas, 1907 May 31; 4p.
    - To Boas, 1907 June 13
    - To Boas, 1907 June 18; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1907 July 1
    - To Boas, 1907 July 3; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1907 July 6
    - To Boas, 1907 July 6
    - To Boas, 1907 July 7; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1907 July 13; 4p.
    - To Boas, 1907 July 16
    - To Boas, 1907 July 20; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1907 Sept. 7
    - To Boas, 1907 Sept. 17; 3p.
    - To Boas, 1907 Oct. 7; 4p.
    - To Boas, 1907 Oct. 10; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1907 Oct. 10
    - To Boas, 1907 Oct. 23; 3p.
    - To Boas, 1907 Oct. 23
    - To Boas, 1907 Oct. 30; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1907 Nov. 5; 4p.
    - To Boas, 1907 Nov. 7; 6p.
    - To Boas, 1907 Nov. 19; 4p.
    - To Boas, 1907 Nov. 20; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1907 Nov. 25; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1907 Dec. 15; 7p.
    - To Boas, 1907 Dec. 16; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1907 Dec. 20; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1907 Dec. 28; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1908 Jan. 18; 4p.
    - To Boas, 1908 Jan. 31
    - To Boas, 1908 Feb. 26; 6p.
    - To Boas, 1908 Mar. 9; 4p.
    - To Boas, 1908 Mar. 21
    - To Boas, 1908 Apr. 4; 3p.
    - To Boas, 1908 Apr. 9; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1908 Apr. 17
    - To Boas, 1908 May 2; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1908 May 9; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1908 May 12
    - To Boas, 1908 May 15
    - To Boas, 1908 May 19
    - To Boas, 1908 June 9; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1908 July 8; 3p.
    - To Boas, 1908 July 18; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1908 Aug. 8; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1908 Aug. 22
    - To Boas, 1908 Sept. 18; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1908 Nov. 7; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1908 Dec. 23
    - To Boas, 1909 Mar. 12; 4p.
    - To Boas, 1909 Sept. 21; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1910 Aug. 13; teleg.
    - To Boas, 1910 Sept. 30; 7p.
    - To Boas, 1911 Dec. 5
    - To Boas, 1911 Dec. 28; 3p.
    - To Boas, 1912 Oct. 2
    - To Boas, 1913 Jan. 15
    - To Boas, 1913 Jan. 28
    - To Boas, 1913 Feb. 18; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1913 Feb. 26
    - To Boas, 1913 Apr. 7
    - To Boas, 1913 Apr. 20
    - To Boas, 1913 Apr. 20
    - To Boas, 1913 June 2
    - To Boas, 1913 June 15; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1913 June 17
    - To Boas, 1913 Aug. 2; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1913 Sept. 28
    - To Boas, 1913 Oct. 22
    - To Boas, 1913 Nov. 27
    - To Boas, 1913 Dec. 23
    - To Boas, 1914 Jan. 5
    - To Boas, 1914 May 1
    - To Boas, 1914 May 31
    - To Boas, 1914 June 2
    - To Boas, 1915 May 5; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1921 Oct. 10; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1921 Nov. 23; 1p.
    - (Enc: his letter to U.S. Ambassador in Berlin. Nov. 21, 1921.), 1924 Nov. 18; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1924 Dec. 3; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1925 Mar. 6; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1925 May 27; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1925 Sept. 10; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1925 Sept. 22; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1925 Nov. 12; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1925 Dec.; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1925 Dec. 16; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1926 Jan. 20; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1926 Feb. 4; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1926 June 22; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1926 July 18; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1927 Nov. 3; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1928 July 19; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1928 Aug. 2; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1928 Dec. 26; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1929 Oct. 18
    - To Boas, 1930 Mar. 11; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1930 May 20; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1930 June 20; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1930 July 26; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1930 Aug. 8; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1930 Sept. 5; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1930 Nov. 13; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1930 Dec. 10; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1931 Mar. 30; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1931 Apr. 14; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1931 May 30; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1931 Oct. 1; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1931 Oct. 13; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1931 Nov. 9; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1931 Nov. 15; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1931 Nov. 21; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1931 Nov. 22; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1931 Dec. 28; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1932 Mar. 29; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1932 Apr. 29; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1932 May 31; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1932 Dec. 3; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1933 Feb. 28; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1933 Dec. 26; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1934 Feb. 28; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1934 July 31; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1936 May 14; 1p.
    - W. Jochelson -- to R.W. Bryan, 1930 Sept. 6; 1p.
    - W. Jochelson -- to R.W. Bryan, 1930 Sept. 28; 1p.
    - W. Jochelson -- to R.W. Bryan, 1930 Oct. 16; 1p.
    - W. Jochelson -- from W.M. Gilbert, 1934 Mar. 15
    - (Enc. with Gilbert, W.M., Mar. 15, 1934)
    - W. Jochelson -- to F.A. Lucas, 1913 Mar. 20
    - W. Jochelson -- from F.A. Lucas, 1913 Apr. 1
    - (Enc. with Lucas, F.A. Apr. 1, 1913), 1913 Dec. 28
    - W. Jochelson -- to U.S. Ambassador in Berlin, 1921 Nov. 21; 2p.
    - W. Jochelson -- to C. Wissler, 1927 May 18; 1p.
  - Jochelson, Mrs. Waldemar (Box 48)
    - From Boas, 1923 May 5; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1923 May 28; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1937 Nov. 13; 1p.
  - Jockers, Ernst (Box 49)
    - From Boas, 1931 Jan. 13; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1931 Jan. 12; 1p.
  - Joerg, W.L.G. (Box 49)
    - From Boas, 1921 Dec. 1; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1921 Nov. 26; 1p.
  - Joest, Wilhelm (Box 49)
    - To Boas, 1886 Mar. 17
  - Johannpeter, Fritz (Box 49)
    - From Boas, 1920 Nov. 3; 1p.
  - Johannsen, O.A. (Box 49)
    - O.A. Johannsen -- to George Engelhardt, 1927 Sept. 11; 1p.
    - (Enc. with letter to Boas, F. from Engelhardt, George), dated 9-27-27
      (Enc: Newspaper Clipping)
  - Johannsen, W.L. (Box 49)
    - From Boas, 1926 Mar. 18; 1p.
  - John Crerar Library (Box 49)
    - From Boas, 1920 Nov. 1; 1p.
  - John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation (Box 49)
    - From Boas, 1929 Dec.; 1p.
    - See Bogoras, W.G. to John Simon Guggenheim Foundation, 1931
    - (Enc. with Bogoras, W.G., Feb. 1, 1931)
    - From Bunzel, R.L., 1930 Dec. 6
  - Johns Hopkins University (Box 49)
    - To Boas, 1886 Jan. 8
      See Livingston, Burton E.
  - Johnson, Alexander (Box 49)
    - From Boas, 1905 May 25
  - Johnson, Alvin (Box 49)
    - From Boas, 1926 May 1; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1926 Dec. 10; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1927 Mar. 14; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1928 Jan. 4; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1928 Oct. 19; 2p.
    - From Boas, 1929 Feb. 19; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1931 Feb. 10; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1931 Mar. 30; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1931 Nov. 30; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1932 Apr. 4; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1932 Dec. 1; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1933 June 19; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1933 Aug. 3; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1933 Oct. 9; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1933 Oct. 20; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1934 Mar. 28; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1934 Nov. 22; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1935 Apr. 17; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1936 Feb. 25; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1937 Feb. 4; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1937 Feb. 18; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1937 Apr. 1; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1937 May 3; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1937 Oct. 28; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1939 Feb. 16; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1940 Feb. 2; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1940 June 3; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1940 Sept. 11; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1940 Oct. 21; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1940 Nov. 18; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1940 Nov. 25; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1941 Oct. 6; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1941 Oct. 6; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1942 Dec. 17; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1905 May 24
    - To Boas, 1906 Mar. 14
    - To Boas, 1926 Apr. 29; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1926 May 3; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1926 July 19; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1926 Oct. 7; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1926 Dec.; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1927 Mar. 15; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1927 June 8; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1928 June 19; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1928 Aug. 16; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1928 Oct. 2; 1p.
    - (Enc: List of topics for the Encyclopedia of the social sciences.), 1928 Oct. 23; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1929 Feb. 26; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1930 July 11; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1931 Feb. 7; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1931 Nov. 20; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1932 Mar. 30; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1932 Apr. 7; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1932 Nov. 22; 1p.
    - (Enc: Staff Memorandum), 1932 Dec. 7; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1933 Mar. 15; 1p.
    - (Enc: Memorandum to Author on "Race"), 1933 Apr. 4; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1933 June 16; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1933 Sept. 21; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1933 Nov. 7; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1934 Mar. 27; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1934 Dec. 5; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1935 Apr. 19; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1935 June 12; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1936 Feb. 24; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1936 Feb. 26; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1937 Jan. 29; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1937 Feb. 5; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1937 Mar. 17; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1937 Dec. 10; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1940 Aug. 14; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1940 Aug. 16; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1940 Aug. 19; 1p.
    - (Enc: Lestoque, Albert n.d.), 1940 Aug. 20; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1940 Sept. 8; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1940 Sept. 13; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1940 Oct. 17; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1940 Oct. 25; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1940 Oct. 31; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1940 Nov. 1; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1940 Nov. 14; 1p.
    - (Enc: MC(traux, A. to Johnson, Alvin Oct. 2, 1940), 1940 Nov. 27; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1941 Oct. 7; 1p.
    - A. Johnson -- from A. Métraux, 1940 Oct. 2
    - (Enc. with Johnson, Alvin, Nov. 14, 1940)
  - Johnson, C. Asapansa (Box 49)
    See Asapansa-Johnson, C.
  - Johnson, Charles S. (Box 49)
    - From Boas, 1925 Apr. 25; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1933 June 23; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1934 Mar. 5; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1925 Apr. 13; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1927 Oct. 18; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1930 June 9; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1933 May 29; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1933 Aug. 11; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1934 Feb. 26; 1p.
    - C.S. Johnson -- to H.R. Bryan, 1933 Dec. 5; 3p.
    - (Enc. with Fauset, C.B., Dec. 12, 1933)
  - Johnson, Douglas W. (Box 49)
    - From Boas, 1914 Feb. 13
    - D. Johnson -- from K.F. Mather, 1931 Apr. 14
    - To Boas, 1931 Apr. 18; 1p.
  - Johnson, Duncan S. (Box 49)
    - D.S. Johnson -- to R.H. Lowié, 1932 May 12; 1p.
  - Johnson, Edward A. (Box 49)
    - From Boas, 1931 Apr. 27; 1p.
  - Johnson, Edwin C. (Box 49)
    - From Boas, 1937 Apr. 12; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1940 June 26; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1937 Apr. 7; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1940 June 26; 1p.
  - Johnson, E.R.F. (Box 49)
    - From Boas, 1934 Dec. 18; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1934 Dec. 13; 1p.
    - (Enc: Suggestions for the establishment of an institute for Latin-American culture researches.), 1936 May 4; 1p.
  - Johnson, F.E. (Box 49)
    - To Boas, 1937 Sept. 21; 1p.
  - Johnson, Franklin W. (Box 49)
    - See Boas, F. Open letter on culture and democracy in Spain. Replies., Jan. 1938
  - Johnson, J.A.C. (Box 49)
    - From Boas, 1913 Jan. 10
  - Johnson, Matthew L. (Box 49)
    - From Boas, 1920 May 22; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1930 June 20; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1933 Jan. 13; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1933 Feb. 10; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1932 Oct. 10; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1933 Jan. 23; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1933 Feb. 6; 1p.
  - Johnson, Mordecai W. (Box 49)
    - From Boas, 1936 Dec. 14; 2p.
    - From Boas, 1937 Jan. 11; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1937 Jan. 20; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1937 May 25; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1937 June 14; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1937 June 17; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1930 May 31; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1936 Dec. 12; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1937 Jan. 18; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1937 Jan. 22; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1937 May 22; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1937 June 3; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1937 June 18; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1937 June 26; 1p.
  - Johnson, Willard (Box 49)
    - To Boas, 1932 Feb. 25; 1p.
  - Johnson, & Collins (Box 49)
    - From Boas, 1909 Jan. 14
  - Johnston, J.B. (Box 49)
    - To Boas, 1937 Sept. 4; telegram
  - Johnston, W.D. (Box 49)
    - From Boas, 1913 Oct. 4
    - From Boas, 1913 Oct. 23
    - From Boas, 1913 Nov. 21
    - To Boas, 1913 Feb. 25
    - To Boas, 1913 May 15
    - To Boas, 1913 Oct. 25
    - To Boas, 1913 Nov. 20
    - To Boas, 1913 Nov. 25; 4p.
  - Johnstone, C. (Box 49)
    - From Boas, 1913 Nov. 5
    - To Boas, 1913 Nov. 3
  - Joly, Henry (Box 49)
    - To Boas, 1938 Jan. 24; 1p.
  - Jones, A.L. (Box 49)
    - From Boas, 1921 Apr. 15; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1929 May 16; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1931 Jan. 29; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1931 Mar. 13; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1931 May 14; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1913 May 14
    - A.L. Jones -- to E. Dijour, 1931 May 16; 1p.
  - Jones, A.M. (Box 49)
    - To Boas, 1917 June 28
  - Jones, C.H. (Box 49)
    - To Boas, 1937 Sept. 4; teleg.
  - Jones, Chester Lloyd (Box 49)
    - C.L. Jones -- to C.R. Miller, 1939 July 5; 1p.
    - (On margin: Miller, C.R. open letter, June 30, 1939)
  - Jones, D. (Box 49)
    - From Boas, 1930 Mar. 29; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1929 Mar. 19; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1930 Mar. 19; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1930 May 14; 2p.
  - Jones, E.K. (Box 49)
    - From Boas, 1939 Jan. 13; 1p.
  - Jones, Herbert William (Box 49)
    - From Boas, 1921 Mar. 7; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1921 Jan. 28; 2p.
  - Jones, Hester (Box 49)
    - From Boas, 1941 June 13; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1941 June 2; 1p.
  - Jones, Jack C. (Box 49)
    - From Boas, 1932 June 3; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1896 Feb. 10
  - Jones, M. (Box 49)
    - From Boas, 1917 Feb. 10
    - To Boas, 1917 Feb. 5
  - Marshall Jones, Publishers (Box 49)
    - To Boas, 1920 Apr. 23; 1p.
  - Jones, Rufus M. (Box 49)
    - From Boas, 1939 Nov. 26; 1p.
  - Jones, S.B. (Box 49)
    - To Boas, 1906 Aug. 27
  - Jones, T.E. (Box 49)
    - From Boas, 1929 Mar. 8; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1929 Mar. 25; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1929 Apr. 2; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1933 Sept. 19; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1929 Mar. 21; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1929 Apr. 8; 2p.
  - Jones, T.J. (Box 49)
    - From Boas, 1927 Oct. 31; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1933 Feb. 13; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1942 Mar. 12; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1929 Jan. 9; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1929 Dec. 28; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1933 Mar. 7; 1p.
    - (Enc: Information for Africans planning to study in U.S.A.), 1936 Feb. 6; 1p.
    - (Enc: Jones, T.J. to Carney, M., Feb. 6, 1936)
    - T.J. Jones -- from C.M. Doke, 1924 Oct. 22
    - T.J. Jones -- to E.C. Parsons, 1924 Dec. 19; 1p.
  - Jones, William (Box 49)
    - From Boas, 1900 Mar. 24; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1900 Mar. 26
    - From Boas, 1903 Aug. 17; 2p.
    - From Boas, 1903 Sept. 22; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1903 Dec. 11; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1905 Nov. 1
    - From Boas, 1906 Feb. 13
    - From Boas, 1906 Mar. 28
    - From Boas, 1906 Sept. 18
    - From Boas, 1907 Jan. 14
    - From Boas, 1907 Jan. 21
    - From Boas, 1907 Jan. 23
    - From Boas, 1907 Feb. 14
    - From Boas, 1907 May 6
    - From Boas, 1907 May 18
    - To Boas, 1904 Aug. 16; 6p.
    - To Boas, 1905 July 10
    - To Boas, 1906 Jan. 30
    - To Boas, 1906 June 18
    - To Boas, 1906 July 1
    - To Boas, 1906 July 25
    - To Boas, 1906 Aug. 6
    - To Boas, 1906 Sept. 7
    - To Boas, 1906 Sept. 21
    - To Boas, 1906 Oct. 22
    - To Boas, 1906 Nov. 21
    - To Boas, 1907 Jan. 10; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1907 Feb. 3; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1907 Apr. 4; postcard
    - To Boas, 1907 Apr. 30; postcard
    - To Boas, 1907 May 15; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1907 May 23
    - To Boas, 1907 July 12; 3p.
    - To Boas, 1907 July 25; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1907 July 28
    - For obituary see Boas, F. May 5, 1909, 1913 Oct. 4; 2p.
  - Jones, William N. (Box 49)
    - From Boas, 1933 Jan. 23; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1933 Jan. 12; 1p.
  - Jones, Weinalt R. (Box 49)
    - From Boas, 1925 Apr. 23; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1925 Mar. 24; 1p.
  - Jonkotka, C. (Box 49)
    - To Boas, 1926 May 4; 2p.
  - Jordon, David Starr (Box 49)
    - From Boas, 1895 June 19; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1895 Oct. 29
    - From Boas, 1920 Mar. 5; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1920 Mar. 26; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1922 Nov. 3; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1922 Dec. 22; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1923 Feb. 19; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1894 Sept. 4; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1894 Nov. 19
    - To Boas, 1895 July 16; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1895 Nov. 4
    - To Boas, 1922 Nov. 9; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1922 Dec. 11; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1923 Feb. 27; 1p.
  - Jordon, V.D. (Box 49)
    - To Boas, 1916 Jan. 8
  - Joseph, D.H. -- see also Newyork Times, Editor (Box 49)
    - To Boas, 1938 Mar. 5; 1p.
    - (Enc: Clipping), 1939 Feb. 25; 1p.
  - Joseph, Nathan (Box 49)
    - To Boas, 1892 Dec. 15; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1894 May 7
  - Joseph, S. (Box 49)
    - From Boas, 1926 May 18; 1p.
  - Josselin de Jong, J.P.B. de (Box 49)
    - From Boas, 1919 Apr. 21; 2p.
    - From Boas, 1919 July 11; 2p.
    - From Boas, 1919 Aug. 24; 2p.
    - From Boas, 1920 Oct. 28; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1920 Nov. 26; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1925 June 26; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1917 Jan. 20
    - To Boas, 1919 Mar. 17; 4p.
    - To Boas, 1919 May 31; 4p.
    - To Boas, 1919 Aug. 1; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1919 Sept. 9; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1920 Nov. 15; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1924 June 27; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1926 July 30; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1931 Sept. 28; 2p.
  - Journal of American Folk-lore (Box 49)
    - To Boas, 1914 Dec.
      (See New Era Printing Co. Prices for reprints)
    - See Deretchin, J., 1920 Sept. 10; 1p.
    - From Williams, H.H., 1919 Oct. 26; 1p.
  - Journal for American Indian Linguistics (Box 49)
    - See Swadesh, M., Feb. 8, 1938
  - Journal of American Oriental Society (Box 49)
    See Montgomery, J.A.
  - Journal of Comparative Neurology (Box 49)
    - Herrick, C. Judson -- to Hodge, F.W., 1899 Apr. 8; 1p.
  - Journal of English and German Philology (Box 49)
    See Goebel, Julius
  - Journal of Nervous and Mental Disease (Box 49)
    See Jelliffe, Smith Ely
  - Journal of Philosophy, Psychology and Scientific Methods (Box 49)
    See Taber, Edith G.
  - Journal of the History of Ideas (Box 49)
    - See Wiener, Philip Paul, Nov. 30, 1938
  - Jovi, Manul (Box 49)
    - To Boas, 1912 June 25
  - Joyce, ? (Box 49)
    - From Boas, 1924 Oct. 29; 2p.
  - Joyce, J. (Box 49)
    - From Boas, 1912 Dec. 27
  - Joyce, P.W. (Box 49)
    - To Boas, 1939 Jan. 17; 1p.
  - Joyce, T.A. (Box 49)
    - From Boas, 1925 Feb. 26; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1925 Mar. 12; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1928 June 8; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1913 Apr. 3
    - To Boas, 1925 Mar. 2; 2p.
    - T.A. Joyce -- to N.M. Butler, 1933 June 2; 1p.
  - Joyce, T.J. (Box 49)
    - From Boas, 1913 Jan. 2
  - Judaeans (Box 49)
    - To Boas, 1934 Mar. 4
      See Kohler, Max J.
  - Judah, E.L. (Box 49)
    - From Boas, 1938 Oct. 13; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1938 Nov. 28; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1938 Nov. 29; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1938 Dec. 3; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1938 Oct. 11; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1938 Nov. 26; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1938 Nov. 30; 1p.
  - Judah, Lionel (Box 49)
    - From Boas, 1937 Nov. 29; 1p.
  - Judd, Charles H. (Box 49)
    - From Boas, 1905 Feb. 27
    - To Boas, 1905 Feb. 23
    - To Boas, 1905 Feb. 28
  - Juden in Polen, 6p (Box 49)
  - Judson, Harry Pratt (Box 49)
    - From Boas, 1914 Feb. 3; 3p.
    - From Boas, 1920 Mar. 5; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1920 Mar. 15; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1920 June 30; 1p.
    - H.P. Judson -- to H. Kraeger, 1906 Aug. 29; 1p.
  - Julia (Box 49)
    See Averkieva, Julia
  - Julius Rosenwald Fund (Box 49)
    - From Boas, 1942 Feb. 5; 1p.
    - To Hurston, Z.N., 1934 Dec. 19; 2p.
  - Juliusburger, O. (Box 49)
    - To Boas, 1933 Oct. 21; 1p.
  - Jung?? (Box 49)
    - To Boas, 1928 June 30; 1p.
  - Junge & Sohn (Box 49)
    - To Boas, 1920 Feb. 12; 1p.
      (Enc: printing estimate?)
    - To Wagner, M.L., 1920 Feb. 17; 1p.
  - Junk, W. (Box 49)
    - From Boas, 1936 Jan. 7; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1936 Dec. 24; 1p.
  - Junkin, Josephine (Box 49)
    - From Boas, 1927 May 23; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1927 May 20; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1927 May 31; 1p.
  - Junod, H.A. (Box 49)
    - From Boas, 1913 Oct. 4
  - Jürgens, A. (Box 49)
    - From Boas, 1927 Feb. 17; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1927 Mar. 25; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1928 Mar. 15; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1930 July 11; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1931 Feb. 4; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1931 May 12; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1931 May 22; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1928 June 20; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1928 June 30; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1928 July 19; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1930 Feb. 17; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1930 July 25; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1931 Jan. 9; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1931 Mar. 25; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1931 June 5; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1932 Feb. 11; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1933 July 7; 1p.
  - Just, E.E. (Box 49)
    - From Boas, 1932 Oct. 14; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1937 Feb. 1; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1932 Oct. 10; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1932 Oct. 13; 1p.
- Franz Boas Papers - Correspondents K
  - K, George F. (Box 49)
    - To Boas, 1907 Apr. 16
  - K., M. (Box 49)
    - To Boas, 1888 Sept. 20; telegram
  - K., Samuel (Box 49)
    - To Boas, 1902 Feb. 27
  - Kaempfert, Waldemar (Box 49)
    - From Boas, 1933 Apr. 10; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1935 Mar. 21; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1936 Apr. 27; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1938 May 26; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1938 Oct. 17; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1938 Oct. 24; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1938 Dec. 5; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1939 Jan. 21; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1939 Feb. 27; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1939 June 22; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1939 June 29; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1940 Feb. 9; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1941 Jan. 2; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1941 Sept. 25; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1933 Apr. 11; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1933 June 12; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1936 Apr. 28; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1938 May 31; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1938 July 28; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1938 Oct. 19; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1938 Dec. 6; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1939 Jan. 23; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1939 Feb. 28; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1939 Aug. 24; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1940 Feb. 6; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1941 Sept. 12; 1p.
  - Kahn, Albert E. (Box 49)
    - From Boas, 1939 Oct. 26; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1939 Feb. 11; 1p.
    - (Enc: List of names Dodd, W.E. to Burlingham, C.C. Feb. 3, 1939), 1939 Feb. 18; 1p.
    - (Enc: Amer. council against Nazi propaganda. Purpose and proposed program. List of members), 1940 Apr. 26; 1p.
  - Kahn, Frau Berta (Box 49)
    - From Boas, 1939 Jan. 3; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1939 Jan. 11; 3p.
  - Kahn, Elinor (Box 49)
    - To Boas, 1942 July 18; 2p.
  - Kahn, M.C. (Box 49)
    - M.C. Kahn -- to M.J. Herskovits, 1928 Jan. 25; 1p.
    - (On margin: Herskovits, M.J., Jan. 2,1928)
  - Kahn, Otto (Box 49)
    - From Boas, 1910 Apr. 28; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1923 Feb. 16; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1923 Feb. 24; 1p.
    - O. Kahn -- to E.L. Boas, 1905 Feb. 23; 1p.
  - Kahra, Kaisar? I.H. (Box 49)
    - From Boas, 1929 Nov. 26; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1929 Nov. 14; 3p.
    - See Urey, H.C., Apr. 22, 1938.
  - Kai Kai, 1931 (Box 49)
    Native American Images note
    Inuit woman
    - Kai Kai, 1931; Black and white photograph of a Plains Indian woman standing outside dwelling, Anadarko, Oklahoma.
      Boas, Franz, 1858-1942
  - Kaiser, I.H. (Box 49)
    - see Urey, H.C., 1938 Spr. 22
  - Kaiser Wilhelm-Institut (Box 49)
    See Haber
  - Kalbach, L.A. (Box 49)
    - To Boas, 1910 June 18
    - To Boas, 1910 June 30
  - Kalibala, Alta J. (Box 49)
    - To Boas, 1938 Jan. 5; 1p.
  - Kalibala, Ernest (Box 49)
    - From Boas, 1933 Jan. 10; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1933 Apr. 19; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1929 May 2; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1929 Sept. 24; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1933 Aug. 12; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1939 Dec. 22; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1939 Dec. 28; 1p.
    - (Enc: Kalibala, E.B. to Carney, Mabel Dec. 28, 1939), 1942 June 4; 1p.
    - E.B. Kalibala -- to Mabel Carney, 1939 Dec. 28; 1p.
    - (Enc. with Kalibala, E.B., Dec. 28, 1939)
  - Kallen, Horace M. (Box 49)
    - From Boas, 1934 Jan. 30; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1934 Feb. 1; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1934 Feb. 6; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1936 July 6; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1933 May 13; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1933 Nov. 21; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1934 Jan. 29; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1934 Jan. 31; 1p.
    - (Enc: International league for academic freedom. Circular letter of invitation to join), 1934 Feb. 7; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1934 Dec. 10; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1934 Dec. 18; 1p.
    - (Enc: Kallen, H.M. to Hirsch, A.H., Dec. 18, 1934)
    - See Lindeman, E.O. June 26, 1936., 1936 Oct. 26; 1p.
    - H.M. Kallen -- to A.H. Hirsch, 1934 Dec. 18; 1p.